<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title/>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher/>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="chapter">
        <head>The Library in the Home</head>

        <pb n="121"/>

        <p>
          <soCalled>"Little and good"</soCalled> is better than big and
          useless. <name type="person">Nimble Jack</name> was too much for the
          giant <name>Blunderbore</name>. The ants do more than the tortoises.
          <name>Old Parr</name>, who died of too much cakes and ale at <name
            type="person">Charles the Second</name>'s court, was a mere boy when
          he died because, in a century and a half, he had not learned as much,
          or done as much, or tried to do as much, as many a village lad who
          marvelled at him and why he went on living when all other folks died
          decently.
        </p>

        <p>
          <name type="person">Plato</name> taught men centuries ago that it is
          far better to learn a little well than a great deal confusedly.
          Smattering is bad both in life and reading. Many a centenarian has only
          smattered through life,and does not know much about it when his book
          of life is shut forever. The same is true of indiscriminate and
          desultory readers. They remind one of those who have no ear for music,
          but think it must be fine in proportion to the loudness of the noise it
          makes.The still small voice is inaudible to them; they want thunder
          from plenty of big drums. Some people's taste in books is like that of
          the <name type="place">New York</name> <hi rend="italic"><foreign
              xml:lang="fr">gamins</foreign></hi> in plays; they must have
          plenty of blood for their money, and the play to suit them must be <q
            type="written">" full of sound and fury, signifying
            nothing."</q>
        </p>

        <p>
          There are certain marks and signs by which one may know the mental
          habits of others, just as a man's good breeding or the reverse may be
          manifested in little things. Good old <name type="person">Launcelot
            Andrews</name>, <name type="title">Bishop of Winchester</name>, in
          the reign of <name type="person">Queen Elizabeth</name>, used to be
        </p>
        
        <pb n="122"/>

        <p>
          very much annoyed by idle visitors who disturbed him while he
          wasstudying in his library of a morning. <q type="spoken"
            who="Launcelot Andrews"> Methink,"</q> said he, <q type="spoken">
          "that they be no true scholars who call upon man before noon."</q> In
          the same way, we may set down a few of the tokens by which the
          sham thinker and shallow reader may be known.
        </p>
 
        <p>
          There are persons-their name is legion-who borrow books as they do
          umbrellas, without the remotest intention of ever returning them. This
          is bad enough, but it is almost as bad to deface, <q
            type="term">"dog'sear,"</q> or tear a book before returning it. Some
          valuable books when they come back to their too kindly owner present
          the appearance of having been used as a portable dinner-table, the
          once unsullied pages wearing the aspect of a greasy table-cloth. This
          is vulgar and indecent, but even worse than this is it to find one's
          book desecrated by the idiotic remarks and egotistic emendations of
          the conceited coxcomb, or, let us charitably hope, silly lunatic, to
          whom in a moment of amiable weakness we lent the cherished volume
          which had solaced many a lonely and enlivened many a leisure hour. The
          shock is almost as great as if we saw again the face of a dear friend
          besmeared with mud by some miserable urchin of the gutter.Nothing has
          ever made a rational being regret his ability to read so much as the
          perusal of these inane, asinine comments and presumed improvements on
          some favorite author, written on the margin.Show us the girl who
          cannot admire a sentence or a sentiment without scrawling <q
            type="written">" very true "</q> or <q type="written"> how beautiful
            "</q> beside it, and we will show you a girl whom the sensible young
          men of her neighborhood will do well to avoid. No rational man would
          make love or offer marriage to one of these feminine annotators. She
          would write her impressions on his shirt front and make remarks upon
          his cuffs. The note-taker, the annotator, the commentator, the critic
          are of course inevitable everywhere, and are well enough in their
          place.
          <q type="written" rend="inline">"A chiel's amang ye takin'
            notes,And, faith, he'll prent it;"</q>
          but that will be in his own book; he will not pencil it in ours.
        </p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
